Jose Simancas

Full-Stack Web Developer

josesimancas51@gmail.com | (+57) 324 5351071

LinkedIn | GitHub

Systems Engineer with over 8 years of experience in web application development, consistently demonstrating dedication and a passion for information technology. Currently seeking new challenges to continue professional growth and expand my knowledge and skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript	HTML5	LESS / SASS	Git / Github	TailwindCSS
Typescript	Php	React	Scrum	GraphQL
Node	Laravel	Redux	CI/CD	Next.js

EXPERIENCES

Shokworks. inc

Prontend Developer

Dic 2019 – Jul 2023

- I developed and maintained frontend interfaces, focusing on web layout, resolving style and functionality issues, and integrating APIs and endpoints.
- I implemented UI/UX design requirements for various projects, primarily using technologies such as React.js and Redux.

SB Medical Miami, United States
Php Developer Jan 2019 – Jun 2019

I developed new content and modules to meet client specifications.

• I maintained 13 e-commerce stores built with Magento 2, ensuring adherence to the development standards in place at that time. This included, among other tasks, updating store templates to implement a responsive design.

Jida Desarrollos C.A.Caracas, VenezuelaPhp DeveloperMay 2018 – Dic 2018

 I maintained various web applications, ensuring compliance with client requirements while using a corporate framework based on PHP.

• I developed multiple minimalist websites in WordPress, providing effective solutions for clients in need of a web portal.

MovilnetCaracas, VenezuelaWeb DeveloperApr 2017 – May 2018

- I gathered and analyzed requirements to design information systems aimed at streamlining and automating the work
 processes of functional users in the Vice Presidency of Commercial Operations.
- I maintained several applications used in the Virtual Channels Management, ensuring their functionality was updated and new requirements were met.

Alcaldía del Municipio Libertador

Caracas, Venezuela

Web Developer Feb 2016 – Mar 2017

- I maintained websites and web applications for the city hall, using PHP, HTML5, and JavaScript within an MVC architecture. This included implementing new functional user requirements and updating existing features.
- I developed new web applications based on the requirements of various city hall departments, aimed at streamlining and automating their work processes.

EDUCATION

Codeable (www.codeable.la)

Intensive full-stack web development educational program with JavaScript (6 months)

Lima, Peru 2024

Universidad Nacional Experimental De La Fuerza Armada

Systems Engineering

Los Teques, Venezuela Sept 2010 – Jul 2017

ADDITIONALLY

Languages:

- Spanish (native)
- English (advanced)

Completed Additional Courses:

- React JS + Redux + ES6: Complete from Beginner to Expert (2021) Certificate
- Learning SOLID Programming Principles (2023) <u>Certificate</u>
- Essential TypeScript (2023) Certificate
- Programming Fundamentals: Databases (2023) Certificate
- EFSET English Certificate: 65/100 (C1 Advanced) Certificate